Come on! Sing with us.
‎来嘛！和我们一起唱
Sorry, Dad, but a family sing-along
‎不好意思 爸爸 全家合唱
isn't gonna make me feel better about moving.
‎不会把我从搬家的痛苦中解脱出来
Look, Syd.
‎听着 小希
‎我知道你会想念布鲁克林
I know you're gonna miss Brooklyn. Okay?
‎但你不会想念 ‎每天早上空气中硫化氢的味道
But you won't miss the smell of hydrogen sulfide every morning.
Because Bridge Hollow smells like… …apples
‎因为桥谷镇的空气闻起来像苹果
and a hint of white privilege.
‎还有一丝白人特权
And it was named "safest small town in the US" last ten years running. So…
‎连续十年被评为 ‎“全美最安全的小镇”
Give Bridge Hollow a chance. Small towns can be full of surprises.
‎给桥谷镇一个机会吧！ ‎小镇可能处处是惊喜
And speaking of surprises…
‎说到惊喜…
‎（吝啬鬼杰克节 万圣夜！）
‎（欢迎来到桥谷镇）
Whoa!
What?
‎什么？
Ahoy there, matey!
‎你们好啊 朋友们！
‎（危险 军事检查站）
Is it me, or did we just drive in to a Party City?
‎是我搞错了吗 ‎还是我们要去戏服店了？
Look! There it is.
‎看！
‎就在这儿
Home sweet home.
‎甜蜜的家
Hey, Syd! Pop quiz.
‎嘿 小希！突击测验
‎如果我们比搬家工 ‎晚离开布鲁克林20分钟
If we left Brooklyn 20 minutes after the movers,
and they show up in the next two, how much faster did we--
‎他们在接下来两分钟内出现 ‎那我们比他们快…
Whoa! Check out those zombies!
‎看看那些僵尸！
Oh yeah. Okay.
‎哦 好吧
That's not disturbing at all.
‎真是一点也不惹人心烦
Hey, babe, let's not invite those neighbors over for dinner.
‎宝贝 我们别请那些邻居来吃晚餐
‎爸爸 既然我们不再住公寓了
Dad, since we're not living in an apartment anymore,
‎也许我们终于可以为万圣节 ‎装点房子了！
maybe we can finally decorate our house for Halloween!
Uh…
-You didn't answer my question. -Mom, can we get a ruling?
‎-你没有回答我的问题 ‎-妈妈 可以判决吗？
‎-好！ ‎-你要带我上家事法庭？
-Yes, I mean-- -You gonna take me to Family Court?
It would be nice to fit in with the neighborhood.
‎能融入社区也不错
But, you know, we're gonna be so busy moving in and getting ready for school.
‎但我们要忙着搬家 准备上学
‎法庭决定支持爸爸
-The court rules in favor of Dad. -Mmm.
I'm sorry, baby.
‎对不起 宝贝
‎也许明年？
Maybe next year?
The system's rigged.
‎体系被操纵了
‎好了 走吧
Okay. Let's go.
It's the movers!
‎搬家工到了！
‎（已售出）
Careful. Fragile package.
‎小心点 易碎品
-Ha, ha, ha. Thank you.
‎谢谢
-Kid's room. Upstairs. -Okay.
‎-孩子的房间 楼上 ‎-好
Hey, neighbor! What's shakin'?
‎嘿 邻居！有什么事？
John Sullivan. But everyone around here calls me Sully.
‎约翰沙利文 但这里的人都叫我沙利
Except for my ex-wife. I don't wanna tell you what she calls me.
‎除了我前妻 ‎我不会告诉你她叫我什么
-Howard Gordon. My wife calls me "honey."
‎霍华德戈登 我妻子叫我“亲爱的”
-That's… That's tough. -Yeah.
‎-那…够了 ‎-好
Well, hey, listen, you picked a hell of a time to move in.
‎听着 你们选择搬进来的时间太不巧
‎如你所见 ‎这里每个人都为万圣节发狂
As you can see, everybody around here kind of goes crazy around Halloween, huh?
Yeah. It's a little ridiculous, right?
‎是啊 有点荒谬吧？
Huh?
‎啊？
‎不 我说的“发狂”是好的那种
No, I meant, uh, "crazy" as in "good."
-Oh yeah. I-- -Yeah.
‎-对 ‎-哦 我…
-Really? Yeah. -Yeah! Yeah.
‎-真的？好 ‎-对！
See, the way it works here is everybody kind of picks a theme,
‎看 是这样的 每个人都会选个主题
and then you go big-time on that theme. Really lean into it.
‎然后你把那个主题做到极致
You gotta commit.
‎你得尽全力
‎今年 我费尽心机
This year, I pulled out all the stops.
‎行尸走肉
The Walking Dead.
-Booyah! Yeah…
‎-轰！ ‎-好吧…
Not a fan. They jumped the shark when they killed Glenn.
‎不喜欢啊 这招都用烂了
Yeah, that was a loss for everybody.
‎好吧 这对大家来说都是损失
-So you got a theme? -No.
‎所以你有主题了？
‎没有
-You like werewolves? -Not particularly.
‎-你喜欢狼人？ ‎-不喜欢
'Cause I got a whole shed full of werewolves.
‎因为我有一堆狼人的东西
That's real wolf fur. I don't even know if it's legal.
‎这是真正的狼皮 ‎我都不知道这是否合法
And I don't care. 'Cause it's Halloween.
‎但我不在乎 因为这是万圣节
Uh, no, thanks. We're good.
‎不用 谢谢 我们不用
‎-真的吗？ ‎-我们不装饰
-Really? -We don't decorate.
‎耶和华见证人
Jehovah's Witness.
No, I… just… think it's… kind of silly.
‎不是 我只是觉得这有点傻
-What? -Do you still believe in Santa Claus?
‎-什么？ ‎-你还相信圣诞老人吗？
‎怎么了？你听说了什么？他没事吧？
Why? What have you heard? Is he okay?
Nice meeting you.
‎很高兴认识你
Great meeting you too, Howard. Hey, you want that werewolf?
‎也很高兴认识你 霍华德 ‎你想要那个狼人吗？
I can get that werewolf into your yard in five minutes. It's not a problem.
‎我可以五分钟后 ‎把那个狼人送进你的院子 没问题
-No, I'm– We're good. -Wife got you on a short…
‎-不…我们不用 ‎-老婆管很严…
-Yeah, I get it. -Go. Turn around. Keep going.
‎-我懂的 ‎-转身 走吧
So, how unhappy do you think Syd is about the move?
‎你觉得希德妮对搬家有多不满？
One to ten?
‎一到十？
They haven't invented a scale big enough to measure this one.
‎远远超过十
‎不知道
I don't know.
‎我感觉她变成了一个我不认识的人了
I feel like she's turning into somebody I don't even recognize anymore.
Well, that's what teenagers do, baby.
‎青少年就会这样 宝贝
They… they grow up. They become their own person.
‎他们会长大 变成独立的个体
‎你得让她长大
And you have to let her.
‎这是什么意思？
And what's that supposed to mean?
You pushed her to be on the science team.
‎你逼她参加科学兴趣班
Yeah, because she loves science.
‎对 因为她喜欢科学
‎科学…很棒
And science…
is awesome.
She wanted to take ballet.
‎她本来想学芭蕾
Right.
‎对
‎但现在 ‎我们的宝贝女儿可以保护自己了
But now, our baby girl can defend herself.
You can't fight off a mugger doing a pirouette.
‎你单脚转圈是没法击退匪徒的
Howard, this isn't Brooklyn.
‎霍华德 这不是布鲁克林
‎这里最可怕的东西 ‎是大家草坪上的装饰
The scariest things around here are the decorations on people's lawns.
-Just…
‎就…
‎给她一点空间
give her some space.
Okay.
‎好
‎我贴起来
I'm putting it up.
‎（吝啬鬼杰克节）
‎看 霍华德！ ‎你不觉得那很适合做我的烘焙店吗？
Look, Howard! Don't you think that would be perfect for my bake shop?
Are you sure about this?
‎你确定吗？
‎开烘焙店跟当律师不一样
Running a bakery is a lot different than being a lawyer.
I'm sure. I even decided on a name.
‎我确定 我把名字都想好了
‎桥谷镇烘焙店
The Bridge Hollow Bakery.
‎最好再想想
Might wanna workshop that one.
‎嘿 妈妈 你会卖
-Hey, Mom. -Huh.
Are you gonna sell things you normally make
‎你平常做的东西还是好吃的东西？
or things that taste good?
Ha ha. I know you guys usually hate on anything without gluten or butter,
‎我知道你们讨厌 ‎不含麸质或黄油的东西
‎但布鲁克林家长会上的妈妈
but the PTA moms in Brooklyn love my sugar-free pumpkin pie
‎超爱我的无糖杏仁酥皮南瓜饼
with almond-powder crust.
-And this town is gonna love them too. -I'm sure they will.
‎-这个小镇也会喜欢的 ‎-我相信他们会的
-Hey, there they are! The Gordons!
‎嘿 他们在这儿！戈登一家！
Baby?
‎宝贝？那个南瓜车里的白人疯婆子 ‎怎么会知道我们是谁？
Why does the crazy white lady in the pumpkin car know who we are?
‎你可能在想
You're probably wondering,
‎“那个南瓜车里的白人疯婆子 ‎怎么会认识我们？”
"How does this crazy white lady in a pumpkin car know who we are?"
‎-没有…对 ‎-塔米赖斯 这里的市长
-No… Yeah. -Tammy Rice. The mayor around here.
Don't be too impressed. It's a volunteer position.
‎不用太佩服 做义工而已
‎我还教钢琴 开优步
I also teach piano and drive an Uber.
You'd be surprised how many people wanna ride in this pumpkin.
‎你都想不到有多少人都想骑这个南瓜
Hey, Howard, your first ride's on me, huh?
‎霍华德 第一次去学校坐我的车吧
-Big science teacher from the big city!
‎大城市来的科学老师！
Ah, no, thank you.
‎不用了 谢谢
And what is all the signs up for Stingy Jack?
‎这个吝啬鬼杰克是怎么回事？
Who is he? The town founder?
‎他是谁？小镇创始人？
Wait, you've never heard of Stingy Jack?
‎你竟然没听说过吝啬鬼杰克？好吧
Okay. Well, I turned his story into a sweater.
‎我把他的故事织成了一件毛衣
-So…
According to an old Irish legend,
‎根据古老的爱尔兰传说
‎曾经有个恶人名叫吝啬鬼杰克
there once lived a wicked man named Stingy Jack.
And he was such a jerk
‎他真的很混蛋
that the villagers finally had enough, and…
‎村民们终于受够了 然后…
But the devil felt sorry for Jack, so he made him a lantern.
‎但恶魔可怜杰克 就给他做了个灯笼
‎用地狱之火刻出的南瓜
A pumpkin carved out with a flame from the fires of hell.
Hmm?
Every Halloween, Jack would return to our town, Bridge Hollow,
‎每年万圣节 ‎杰克会回到我们的小镇 桥谷镇
to seek his revenge on the descendants of the villagers who did him in.
‎报复杀了他的村名
Well, that's what we tell the tourists. Am I right?
‎我们跟游客都是这么说的 对吧？
‎等等 所以南瓜灯叫杰克灯！
Wait, so that's why they call them jack-o'-lanterns!
Hey, Syd, what do you say we go hit up the local museum
‎嘿 小希 不如我们去当地的博物馆
where we can learn some actual facts.
‎了解一些事实吧
Uh, no. I'm gonna explore this town
‎不 我要探索这个小镇
and find something that's actually fun to do.
‎找点有意思的事情做
‎她会没事的 ‎这是美国最安全的小镇 记得吗？
She'll be fine. Safest small town in the US, remember?
That's right, but don't let any of those sore losers in Oaktown
‎没错 ‎但别让奥克城的怂包听到你说的话
hear you say that.
‎他们甚至排不进前十
They didn't even make the top ten.
Uh, so, is there gonna be any food at this festival?
‎这个节日庆典会有吃的吗？
‎当然 很多当地的店铺都设有摊位
Of course! Yeah, a lot of the local stores are setting up booths.
‎有热狗 漏斗蛋糕 浓汤
We got hot dogs, funnel cakes, chowder, everything.
Uh, is there gonna be any artisanal vegan baked goods?
‎会不会有手工烘焙的食物？
Hmm. I don't know what that means. But sure, why not?
‎我不知道那是什么意思 不过当然了
‎（桥谷镇公墓 服务部入口）
Whoa!
-You okay? -Yeah, I'm good. Thanks.
‎-你没事吧？ ‎-我很好 谢谢
‎你们在这里做什么？
What were you guys doing in there?
Grave-digging.
‎盗墓
You can get really good money on the dark web for a fully intact corpse.
‎在暗网上卖完整的尸体很赚钱
‎我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
Show her, Mario.
‎给她看看 马里奥
Um, testing out this new spectral EM four detection app.
‎在测试这个离子探测器应用程序
It measures electromagnetic field fluctuations.
‎能测量电磁场的波动
Which is what happens
‎当空气中的电荷被扰乱
whenever the electrical charges in the air are disturbed by a--
‎就会发生这种现象…
Ghost or other paranormal phenomena.
‎被鬼或其他超自然现象扰乱
So, what are you guys?
‎你们是什么人？
‎比如桥谷镇超自然学会之类的？
Like, the Bridge Hollow High Paranormal Society or something?
‎看见没？我就说这T恤很烂
See? I told you the shirts were lame.
No, I like them.
‎不 我很喜欢
Who is this girl?
‎这女孩是谁？
Guys, don't be weird.
‎伙计们 别这么奇怪
I'm Jamie. That's Ramona. This is Mario.
‎我是杰米 那是蕾梦娜 这是马里奥
Sydney.
‎希德妮
Wait. Sydney Gordon?
‎等等 希德妮戈登？
You and your folks just moved to the old Hawthorne house.
‎你一家人刚搬到霍桑原来的家
The what house?
‎什么家？
Come on. There's something you need to see.
‎来 有件事你需要知道
Madam Hawthorne. One of the preeminent spiritualist mediums of the 20th century.
‎霍桑夫人 20世纪最伟大的灵媒之一
‎她以前就住在你家
She lived and died in your house.
‎有传言说她可能还住在那里
Rumor has it she might still be there.
Wait, so I might live in a haunted house?
‎等等 我可能住在鬼屋里？
This place just got a lot cooler.
‎这个地方变得更酷了
‎所以你喜欢这种东西
So, you're, like, into this kind of stuff.
Yeah. Kinda. I was gonna start a Paranormal Club at my school, but…
‎有点 我本来想在学校里 ‎开超自然俱乐部的 但…
You didn't wanna be a social leper.
‎你不想做异类
No. My dad wanted me to join the science team instead.
‎不是 我爸想让我加入科学小组
Wow, he… sounds so… awesome.
‎哇 他听起来好棒
So, have you experienced anything strange in your house since you moved in?
‎所以你搬进去后 ‎有经历过什么怪事吗？
-Cold drafts? -Power fluctuations?
‎-冷风？ ‎-能量波动？
Voices from beyond the grave?
‎坟墓里的声音？
Well, I did hear this weird noise the other night,
‎那天晚上我听到了奇怪的声音
and it was definitely not the house settling.
‎肯定不是房子咯吱作响
Well, in that case, we have some homework for you.
‎这样的话 我们有作业给你
Okay, not exactly sure how this works,
‎好 不确定这具体是怎么用的
‎就当打水漂了
but here goes nothing.
‎（灵媒板）
‎霍桑夫人
Madam Hawthorne.
‎你能听到我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
H…
‎H…
E…
‎E…
R…
‎R…
Here?
‎这里？
‎你在这儿？
You're here?
‎有人吗？
Hello?
‎（照片）
"SJ 1927."
‎SJ 1927
Ah!
Mmm.
‎你们不会相信 但这房子闹鬼
So you guys are not gonna believe this,
but this house is totally haunted.
What?
‎-什么？ ‎-不！是真的！
-No! For real!
By an old Gypsy woman named Hawthorne.
‎是一个叫霍桑的吉普赛老妇人
She used to live here in this house.
‎她以前住在这里
And for some reason, she gave me her pumpkin, but…
‎不知为何 她把她的南瓜给我了 但…
Oh, I get it. And that's why we should move back to Brooklyn.
‎明白了 所以我们应该搬回布鲁克林
I'm not making this up. Haven't you heard all the freaky noises?
‎这不是我编的 ‎你没听到那种怪声吗？
It's an old house, sweetie. Old houses are like old people.
‎这是幢老房子 亲爱的 ‎老房子就像老人
-They make freaky noises. -Yeah, and they're drafty.
‎-会发出奇怪的声音 ‎-没错 容易漏风
It's the wood. It expands. It contracts.
‎是木头 会扩张 会收缩
‎不是鬼 是科学
It's not ghosts. It's science.
Let me tell you what happened. I was using the Ouija board app--
‎让我告诉你发生了什么事 ‎我在用通灵板应用程序…
Oh, come on. A Ouija board is nonsense,
‎拜托 通灵板都是胡说八道
and an app is even worse.
‎还搞个应用程序出来
What's the ghost supposed to do? Get a Wi-Fi password?
‎鬼魂会怎么做？找无线网络的密码？
Ow!
I don't know why I even bothered. I should have known.
‎我不知道我为什么还在意 ‎我早该知道…
Known what?
‎知道什么？
That you would make fun of me for believing in things like this.
‎你会嘲笑我相信这种事
‎就像你平常一样
Just like you always do.
I… I do not. Do I… do I make fun…
‎我没有 我会取笑你吗？
You just did.
‎你刚刚就取笑了
Well, it's not what I meant.
‎我不是那个意思
I just want you to start looking at the world scientifically.
‎我只是想让你用科学的眼光看世界
Then you'll realize that all these crazy things
‎然后你会发现这些疯狂的事情
‎有更现实的解释
have a much more realistic explanation.
So you weren't making fun of me. You just think I'm stupid. Okay.
‎所以你没有嘲笑我 ‎你只是觉得我蠢 好的
‎等等 我没说你蠢！
Wait. I… I didn't say you were stupid!
‎只是无知
Just ignorant.
-I'm about to smack you.
‎我要打你了
‎（桥谷镇高中 ‎第60届万圣节庆典 今夜）
‎（共存）
Oh! There he is! In the flesh. The man, the myth, the legend.
‎他本人现形了 ‎那个男人 那个传说 那个神话
Principal Pretty-Boy Floyd.
‎帅哥校长弗洛伊德
‎很高兴又见到你
Good to see you again, buddy.
Thanks for the help getting us settled. I appreciate it.
‎谢谢你帮我们安顿下来
Oh, no, Howard. Thank you for stepping in midsemester.
‎不 霍华德 ‎谢谢你学期中加入我们教课
You really saved my behind.
‎你真是我的救命恩人
‎维韦罗斯老师中彩票
Boy, when Mr. Viveros won the lottery
and took off to Key West with his mistress,
‎和他的情妇私奔去了基韦斯特
‎这事让我们太难办了
it really put us in a pickle.
-Yeah… -Oh…
-You don't play the lottery, do you? -No.
‎-你不买彩票 对吧？ ‎-不买
Okay.
‎好
-And the marriage? -Solid.
‎那婚姻呢？
-Really? -Jay-Z/Beyoncé.
‎-好得很 碧昂丝夫妇那样 ‎-真的？
-I'll show you the classroom. -All right.
‎-我带你去教室 ‎-好吧
Well, here it is.
‎就是这儿
‎去看看
Check it out.
Wow! We didn't have all this in Brooklyn.
‎我们在布鲁克林可没这些
-Yeah. -This is great.
‎-对 ‎-太好了
Brand-new microscopes.
‎全新的显微镜
-Yeah. Mm-hmm. -Bunsen burner at every station.
‎-对 ‎-每个课桌都有本生灯
-These are yours now. -Thank you.
‎-都是你的了 ‎-谢谢
-We got a brand-new sterilizer here. -Nice.
‎-这儿有个全新的消毒器 ‎-真好
-Chemical cabinet, fully stocked. -Okay.
‎-药品柜 存货充足 ‎-好
-Whoa!
Ah, look at this!
‎看看！
The kids on the science team rigged this one up for you.
‎科学小组的孩子们为你设计了这个
-You like it? -No, no, no.
‎-你喜欢吗？ ‎-不
They call him Albert Spine-stein.
‎他们叫他阿尔伯特骷髅斯坦
Get-- Ooh.
‎把…
Get… Get him off.
‎把它拿开
That's funny.
‎有意思
Did we get you?
‎吓到你了吗？
Yeah, you got me.
‎吓到我了
Yeah, Howard.
‎好 霍华德
Come on in, kids.
‎进来吧 孩子们
This is, uh, Mr. Gordon, your new science teacher.
‎这是戈登先生 你们新来的科学老师
He'll be with you for the rest of the semester.
‎接下里的学期都是他来教你们了
I have never been so scared. When I opened the trunk,
‎我从来没有这么害怕过 ‎我打开后备箱时
I thought it was gonna be, like, this severed head inside.
‎我以为里面会有个人头
‎原来只是个破南瓜
Turned out it was just some broke-ass pumpkin.
Oh, that reminds me. I…
‎让我想起来了
I don't know what you got planned for tonight,
‎我不知道你今晚有什么计划
but we'll be back up at the school,
‎但我们会回到学校 装扮“恐怖大厅”
working the… the "Halls of Horror."
You should come. It's… sick.
‎你可以一起来 超酷
We go every year. So it's obviously super cool.
‎我们每年都去 所以显然超级酷
Okay. It's a little cheesy.
‎好 有点俗气
But everyone wears a costume, and it's fun to check them all out.
‎但所有人都穿着戏服 ‎看看也蛮有意思
Yeah, sounds really cool, guys, but I don't really have a costume.
‎对 听起来很酷 但我没有戏服
My family doesn't really do Halloween.
‎我家人不喜欢过万圣节
What does that even mean?
‎那是什么意思？
It's my dad's thing to hate on Halloween. He says he thinks it's stupid.
‎我爸最讨厌万圣节了 他觉得很蠢
This guy just doesn't get it.
‎真是少根筋的家伙
‎但我觉得出于某种愚蠢的原因
But I honestly think, for some dumb reason,
it actually freaks him out.
‎这让他害怕
No pressure, but you know where to find us if you change your mind.
‎别有压力 若你改变心意 ‎你知道去哪里找我们
-Okay. -Bye.
‎-好 ‎-再见
Hmm. Screw it.
‎该死
‎（吝啬鬼杰克节）
‎（桥谷镇烘焙坊）
-Hey, do you want a headband? -Oh! Thanks.
‎-你想要头带吗？ ‎-谢谢
-Trick or treat!
‎不给糖就捣蛋
Oh!
‎小鬼 永远不要袭击黑人
Kid, never ever jump out the bushes on a Black man.
Leave candy on your porch next time. It's Halloween.
‎下次把糖果留在门廊上吧 ‎今天是万圣节
Boy, you better get your little behind off my… property.
‎小子 你最好离开我的地盘
Aw, come on, Sully.
‎来吧 沙利
A rubber bat.
‎橡胶球棒
‎不
Trick or treat!
‎希德妮
Sydney!
‎嗨 爸爸
Hi, Dad.
Okay.
‎好
Okay. I see what you're doing.
‎好 我知道你在干什么
‎我在干什么？
What am I doing?
If I had to guess, I'd say trying to annoy me.
‎要我猜 我会觉得你想惹怒我
No, I'm trying to have fun. Annoying you is just the bonus.
‎不 我是在找乐子 惹怒你只是加分项
Look, I'm sorry if you thought I was making fun of you.
‎如果你觉得我是在取笑你 我很抱歉
And for moving me here.
‎还有逼我搬家
-I did that for our family. -And for treating me like a child.
‎-我这么做是为了家人 ‎-还有把我当孩子看待
You are a child.
‎你就是个孩子
Do you want to know something, Dad? I'm done being treated like a baby.
‎你知道吗 爸爸？ ‎我受够了被像小孩一样对待
I'm 14. I can make my own decisions,
‎我14岁了 我可以自己做决定
starting with what holidays I choose to celebrate.
‎从选择我庆祝什么节日开始
Oh, and you know that science team you love so much?
‎你知道你最爱的科学小组吗？
‎我讨厌死了 我退出了
Yeah, well, I hate it, and I quit.
Yeah?
‎是吗？
Well, how about this?
‎不如这样？你被禁足了
You're grounded.
‎什么？为什么？
What? Why?
Because I'm your father, and I said so.
‎因为我是你父亲 我就这么说了 ‎回你的房间
Now go to your room.
Hmm?
‎你听到了 回你的房间
You heard me. I said, go to your roo--
Cute. Little trick candle?
‎真不错 吹不灭的小蜡烛？
Little magnesium on the wick?
‎灯丝上放了点镁？
I got something for you. Hmm? How about that? Hmm?
‎看看我的厉害 怎么样？
What about that?
‎怎么样？
Okay.
‎好
‎我很厉害吧？
How do you like those apples?
You and your little tricks. Thinking you all grown.
‎你和你的小把戏 以为你长大了
-Dad, it was still lit!
‎爸爸 还是亮的
‎放轻松 唾液中和了…搞什么…
-Relax. Saliva neutralized-- What the…
Oh shit!
‎我靠！
Hey, watch your mouth!
‎嘿 说话小心点 该死！
-Ah, shit! Shit!
Ah!
Oh!
Come here! Come.
‎过来！
I can't believe you brought a bat into our home!
‎真不敢相信你把蝙蝠带进我们家！
Dad! Do you really think I went into some cave,
‎爸爸！你真以为我去了某个山洞
found a live bat, and brought it home?
‎找到了活着的蝙蝠 把它带了回来？
Not all bats live in caves.
‎不是所有蝙蝠都住在洞穴里
Actually, some species, they live under bridges or in trees.
‎有一些品种住在桥下 或者是树里
You know, it's funny, the western red bat--
‎有趣的是 红毛尾蝠…
Dad, the bat isn't real!
‎爸 蝙蝠不是真的！
-Whoa!
‎看起来很真实！
It sure looked real to me!
Where is it?
‎在哪里？
I don't know.
‎我不知道
Dad!
‎爸爸！
Look how much candy I got.
‎看我拿回来多少糖果！
If you're trying to annoy me,
‎如果你想惹恼我
it worked.
‎起作用了
Oh, it worked.
‎真起作用了
Uh, Dad, I think something really weird is going on.
‎爸 我觉得这事真的很奇怪
-And I'm gonna find out what it is. -Oh, no, you're not.
‎-我会搞清楚是怎么回事 ‎-你不会
‎你被禁足了 记得吗？
You're grounded, remember?
Wait, who… who are you calling?
‎等等 你要打给谁？
‎你打给上帝我都不在乎 我说了
You can call God for all I care, so… I said what I said.
-Hey, Syd, what's up? -Mom, there's some spooky sh…
‎-嘿 小希 怎么了？ ‎-妈妈 今晚发生了…
"stuff" happening tonight. I know it sounds weird,
‎一些诡异的事 ‎我知道这听起来很奇怪
but the Halloween decorations are coming to life.
‎但万圣节装饰都活过来了
I want to find out what's going on, but Dad won't let me.
‎我想知道是怎么回事 但爸爸不让
Gimme the phone.
‎把电话给我
-Emily, listen, your daughter is trippin'. - No. Think about your daughter.
‎-艾米丽 听着 你女儿疯了 ‎-不 你要考虑一下自己的女儿
She wanted to stay in Brooklyn. And you said no.
‎她想留在布鲁克林 你拒绝了
-I know, but you-- -She wanted to decorate the house.
‎-我知道 但你… ‎-她想装饰房子
And you said no.
‎你拒绝了
She wanted to take ballet.
‎她想学芭蕾
-Baby, you said no. -But… but that's for her safety.
‎-宝贝 你又拒绝了 ‎-但这是为了她的安全
We are not saying no to this. It's Halloween. Let her have some fun.
‎这个不能拒绝了 ‎今天是万圣节 让她开心一点
‎换免提
Put me on speaker.
The court rules in favor…
‎法庭判决…
of Sydney.
‎希德妮胜
-Yes! Damn.
‎-太好了！ ‎-该死
The system works.
‎体系还是挺管用的
Okay.
‎好
‎你可以去 但我跟你一起
You can go, but I'm going with you.
-What? -Look.
‎-什么？ ‎-听着
Halloween brings out all the crazies, even in a safe town like this.
‎万圣节会唤起所有的疯狂 ‎即使是在这样安全的小镇
No. Mm-mm. Tomorrow, you get space. Tonight, you get me.
‎不 明天给你空间 今晚你得和我一起
‎法庭同意！
Court agrees!
Yeah!
‎耶！
Have fun, you guys.
‎祝你们玩得开心
Come by the Stingy Jack Festival. I have treats waiting.
‎来吝啬鬼庆典看看 我有准备零食
Brains…
‎大脑…
Don't worry, kids. These, uh, zombies won't bite.
‎别担心 孩子们 这些僵尸不会咬人
Or will they?
‎会吗？
I'm just busting your beans. Get in there. Get the good stuff.
‎我逗你们的 进来吧 来拿好吃的
Booyah!
‎嘿哈！
That worked too good. That was too good.
‎效果太好了
You should've seen your faces. You look ridiculous.
‎你该看看你的表情 太荒谬了
You got nailed. You got smoked.
‎你被耍了
I'm just kidding. You guys recovered. That was a good recovery. I like that.
‎我开玩笑的 你们恢复得很好 我喜欢
Come on, grab some stuff here.
‎来吧 来拿东西
There you go. That's for you. Little something for you.
‎好了 这是给你的
A couple for you. There you go.
‎给你一点 好了
Enjoy it.
‎好好享受吧
You're welcome.
‎不客气
Be careful out there. A lot of freaks.
‎小心点 怪胎很多
‎去睡觉了 沙利文先生
Back to bed, Mrs. Sullivan.
Eh.
Come on.
‎来吧
‎搞什么…
What the…
‎你们从哪里来的？
Where'd you come from?
‎滚出去 快点好吗？
Hey, get out of here. Beat it. Will ya?
-Feisty little one, huh?
‎这小家伙有点脾气啊？
Didn't see that coming, did you?
‎没料到吧？
All right, let's go. Get out of here.
‎好了 走吧 出去
‎看见没 爸爸？我跟你说了
See, Dad? I told you.
The bat's eyes were glowing red, just like this pumpkin.
‎蝙蝠的眼睛泛红光 ‎就像这个南瓜一样
Just like the witches from across the street.
‎就像街对面的女巫一样
‎对
Right.
Witches coming to life.
‎女巫复活了
Okay. So what's your plan?
‎好 你有什么计划？
Drive around town, looking for Halloween decorations with red eyes?
‎开车到镇上 ‎找红眼睛的万圣节装饰？
Someone has to do something, and it might as well be--
‎总得有人做点什么 不如是…
Wait, Syd. Where are you going?
‎等等 小希 你要去哪里？
Get off me!
‎放开我！
Brains…
‎脑子…
What the…
‎搞什么…
-Brains… -Whoa!
‎-脑子… ‎-脑子…
Oh yeah. Oh yeah.
‎好的
Oh, come on now. Oh, here we go.
‎来吧 就这样
Now those are some impressive animatronics.
‎这些电子玩具真的很厉害
Way more impressive than a… stupid werewolf in the shed.
‎比棚里的蠢狼人厉害多了
Eat lead, bastard!
‎鬼玩人的死混蛋！
Oh yeah.
‎耶！
Oh! That worked. Okay.
‎有用吗？好
Come on. Well…
‎来吧…
Oh no!
‎不！
Brains…
‎脑子…
Now, that's a bit much.
‎有点过分了
Dad, we have to do something.
‎爸 我们得做点什么
It-- Relax, Syd. Okay?
‎放轻松 小希 好吗？
He's just putting on a show for the trick-or-treaters.
‎他只是在给讨糖果的人表演
-Although, that is disturbingly realistic.
‎不过逼真得有点吓人了
-I'll do it myself. -Wait. Syd, wait.
‎-我自己来 ‎-等等 小希
What? Hey, what are you gonna do?
‎什么？那你打算怎么办？
-That… that's not nice, Sydney. -Oh, yeah!
‎这可不好 希德妮
That was awesome! Oh! Good job.
‎太棒了！漂亮
‎脑子…
Brains…
‎好 那…够了 各位
Okay, that-- All right. That's enough play, guys.
Brains…
‎脑子…
-Booyah! -Holy cow!
‎-嘿哈！ ‎-我靠！
‎小希 你还好吗？
Syd, are you okay?
What happened here? Did all these things short-circuit?
‎怎么回事？这些东西都短路了？
I'll tell you what happened here. One of these zombies just bit me! Huh?
‎我告诉你发生了什么 ‎一个僵尸咬了我！
‎天啊 我会变成其中一员吗？
Oh God. Does that mean I'm gonna turn into one of them?
Is that how this works?
‎是这样的吗？
You can't let me turn. You gotta shoot me. Blow my head off, man.
‎你不能让我变身 ‎你要开枪打我 把我的头打掉
What? No, I'm not gonna shoot you!
‎什么？我不会开枪的！
-I don't wanna turn into a zombie! -You're not gonna turn into a zombie!
‎-我不想变成僵尸！ ‎-你不会变成僵尸的！
-Zombies are fictional creations. Okay?
‎僵尸是虚构的 好吧？
Dead bodies don't have functioning nervous systems,
‎死尸没有神经系统
which means they can't move.
‎它们动不了
Basic biology.
‎基本生物学
I didn't understand a single word you just said.
‎完全不懂你在说什么
‎以防万一 我应该把自己铐在门廊上
Maybe I should handcuff myself to the porch just in case.
Or you can get a tetanus shot.
‎或者你可以注射破伤风
‎说得好 科学哥
Yeah. Good call, Bill Nye the Science Guy.
-Burn.
‎厉害吧
You smoked.
‎嘲的就是你
‎爸爸 僵尸的眼睛也红了
Dad, the zombies' eyes were glowing red
just like the bat and like the flame in Hawthorne's pumpkin.
‎就像蝙蝠 就像霍桑南瓜里的火焰
This all has something to do with her. I know it does.
‎这一切都跟她有关
-I'm gonna try to contact her.
‎-我要联系一下她 ‎-拜托
Oh, come on, not the Ouija board app. Give me a break.
‎不会又是通灵软件 放过我吧
Maybe there's another option we can explore.
‎也许我们还有别的选择
‎好 你有什么建议？我洗耳恭听
Okay. What do you suggest? I'm all ears.
How do you propose we talk to Hawthorne? She's dead.
‎我们要怎么跟霍桑谈？她死了
No, she's not.
‎她没死
No.
-You're talking about old Madam Hawthorne?
‎你说的是老霍桑夫人？
‎对
Yeah. Oh yeah.
‎她和那些吃脑子的混蛋一样 都死了
She's as dead as one of these brain-eating bastards.
But her granddaughter Victoria…
‎但她的孙女维多利亚
…she's still sucking air.
‎还在呼吸
‎不…
No…
‎（暗影苹果树 退休之家）
Even the retirement home is decorated?
‎退休之家都有装饰？
-Who wants to trick-or-treat here?
‎谁想在这里讨糖果？
‎保持警惕 ‎随时随地可能有人发动攻击
Stay alert. An attack could come from anywhere at any time.
Yeah. We're in real danger here.
‎对 我们这里真的很危险
‎烂瓜？
A bumpkin?
‎不 南瓜
No. A pumpkin. With a "P."
It belonged to your grandmother, Josephine Hawthorne.
‎属于你祖母约瑟芬霍桑
That wasn't no pumpkin. It was a turnip.
‎那不是南瓜 是萝卜
No, actually, I'm pretty sure it was a pumpkin.
‎不 我很确定是南瓜
I know a soddin' turnip when I see one, Chachi.
‎我能认出萝卜 恰奇
-Chachi? -Miss Hawthorne.
‎-恰奇？ ‎-霍桑小姐
Can you tell us about the turnip?
‎能跟我们说说萝卜的事吗？
Ah… It… It was a long time ago.
‎那是很久以前的事了
I got this, Syd.
‎交给我吧 小希
Look.
‎你看
‎我不想待在这里太久
I don't wanna be here any longer than I have to be, so…
Oh!
Take it easy.
‎悠着点
You can have this after you tell my daughter
‎你告诉我女儿她想知道的
everything she wants to know.
‎这个就归你
-Okay?
‎好吗？
How y'all doing? You need any juice?
‎那是一个月黑风高的夜晚
It was a dark and stormy night.
Of course it was.
‎当然
‎-为什么从来没有潮湿的阳光… ‎-我的天哪…
-Why is it never humid and sunny– -Oh my God…
Okay, go.
‎你说
Mystics from all over the world
‎来自世界各的神秘术士
showed up to our house at the behest of my Grandma Jo.
‎在我祖母的召唤下来到我们家
Madam Hawthorne.
‎霍桑夫人
‎快点 我们时间不多了
Hurry, we don't have much time.
It's almost midnight.
‎快半夜了
‎他们的计划是用她的魔法书
Their plan was to use her grimoire,
‎一本写满了古老咒语的书
a book of ancient spells.
All right. Let's get to bewitching.
‎好吧 开始念咒
‎他们举办了一场圣灵召唤大会
They held a séance to conjure the spirit himself
and finally put an end to the curse of Stingy Jack.
‎终于结束了吝啬鬼杰克的诅咒
‎等等 吝啬鬼杰克 他是真的？
Wait. Stingy Jack. He's real?
He's real, all right.
‎他是真的
I seen him with my own two eyes.
‎我亲眼看见的
With those two eyes?
‎用你现在的眼睛？
-Stop. -Okay, I'm sorry. Continue.
‎-别这样 ‎-对不起 继续
That old lantern was a gift from the devil himself.
‎那个旧灯笼是魔鬼送的礼物
‎让杰克能在凡间和灵界之间移动
'Twas what allowed Jack to move between this world and the spirit world
so that every Halloween,
‎这样每个万圣节
he could torment the folks of Bridge Hollow.
‎他都能折磨桥谷镇的人
‎但他们说好了 他只能在这儿
But the deal was he could only stay here
from sundown till midnight.
‎从日落待到午夜
Midnight, Eastern Standard Time?
‎东部标准时间的午夜？
-Dad. -What?
‎-爸 ‎-怎么了？
But Jack wasn't satisfied with just one night a year.
‎但杰克不满足于一年只待一晚
He wanted every night to be Halloween.
‎他希望每晚都是万圣节
‎结果发现有个漏洞
Turns out there was a loophole.
Jack could stay in our world forever,
‎杰克可以永远停留在我们的世界
‎任由他制造混乱
free to spread his mayhem
if, at the stroke of midnight,
‎如果在午夜时
he found another soul to take his place in the ever after.
‎他能找到另一个灵魂替他去阴间
But on Halloween night, 1927,
‎可是在1927年的万圣节之夜
my Grandma Jo put an end to the old bastard's plan.
‎我祖母终结了那个混蛋的计划
Using magic to trap the ghost of Stingy Jack
‎用魔法把杰克的鬼魂
inside his own lantern.
‎困在他自己的灯笼里
‎再见了 杰克
So long, Jack.
‎只要那个旧灯笼不被点燃
As long as that old lantern remains unlit,
you kids got nothing at all to worry about.
‎你们就没啥可担心的
Ew!
What if we kind of sort of relit it?
‎万一我们重新点燃了怎么办？
Oh, then you're screwed.
‎那你们就完蛋了
-Hey, Tammy, how are you? -Not great.
‎塔米 你好吗？
‎不太好 很多人报警说
Been getting lots of reports of decorations
‎自家草地上的装饰失踪了
going missing from people's lawns.
‎那些橡树镇的小流氓就爱恶作剧
Those Oaktown hoodlums sure love pulling pranks.
-So, what do we have here? -Oh, well, help yourself.
‎-这里有什么？ ‎-请自便
‎你在这里看到的一切都无麸质 ‎不含大豆 纯素食
Everything you see here is gluten-free, soy-free, and vegan.
Oh. Just what people want on Halloween. Healthy snacks.
‎正是人们在万圣节想要的健康零食
‎来 试试这个
Here. Try this.
It is a red velvet muffin
‎这是用甜菜根代替人工染料
made with beetroot instead of artificial dyes.
‎做的红丝绒松饼
Hmm.
Wow.
You can really taste the beetroot.
‎你能尝到甜菜根的味道
-Mm-hmm. -Mm-hmm.
You got your beet. You got your root.
‎有甜菜 也有根
‎都混进去了
All mixed in there.
-Yes. -Hey, have you seen our Stingy Jack?
‎-是的 ‎-你看到我们的吝啬鬼杰克了吗？
No…
‎没…
‎南瓜雕刻大赛的优胜者
So the winner of the pumpkin carving contest…
-Mm-hmm. -…gets placed on top as the head.
‎会被放到那个头上
I'm gonna go get something to wash it down.
‎我去喝点什么把这水泥冲下去
Whoo. Gets… gets you in a chokehold.
‎要噎死我了
‎所以你觉得呢？
So, what do you think?
‎我觉得地窖守护仙女跟疯子差不多
I think Crypt Keeper fairy girl is one bird short of a cuckoo clock.
And that old lantern is clearly a pumpkin.
‎那个旧灯笼显然是个南瓜
Dad. Seriously? What if Victoria's telling the truth?
‎爸 真的吗？ ‎如果维多利亚说的是真的呢？
What if it wasn't Madam Hawthorne I was talking to on that Ouija board?
‎万一在通灵板上和我说话的 ‎不是霍桑夫人呢？
What if it was Stingy Jack who tricked me into finding his old lantern.
‎万一是吝啬鬼杰克 ‎骗我去找他的旧灯笼呢？
‎然后当我重新点燃它时 ‎我唤醒了他 放出了他
Then, when I relit it, I woke him up or let him out,
and now he's making all the Halloween decorations come to life.
‎他让所有万圣节装饰都活过来了
Oh, come on, Syd.
‎拜托 小希
Halloween decorations coming to life? That's just not something that happens.
‎万圣节装饰活过来了？那是不可能的
Now that is a great costume.
‎这个装扮栩栩如生
Kind of poor taste for a nursing home though.
‎但真的很不适合养老院
‎不 今天不行
Nope, not today.
Oh, wow.
‎那看起来就像澳大利亚漏斗网蜘蛛
That looks just like an Australian funnel-web spider.
‎学名“阿特拉斯罗伯特斯”
Atrax robustus.
Um…
Is that bad?
‎那不好吗？
Well, it would be. If it was real.
‎要是真的就不好了
Good thing these are just plastic.
‎幸好这些只是塑料
Boop!
They're alive!
‎是活的！
‎不可能
It's impossible.
Oh!
Stay here.
‎待在这里
Okay.
‎好
Uh…
Aha!
Ah!
Hey, Syd! Pop quiz.
‎嘿 小希！突击测验
What chemicals found in common household cleaning supplies
‎居家清洁用品中的什么化学物质
can be combined to create a highly acidic solvent?
‎能混合产生酸性极高的溶剂？
Maybe now is not the time for a science lesson!
‎也许现在不是上科学课的时候？
You got a good point there.
‎你说得有道理
I had it set to "mist."
‎我得设为喷雾模式
It would've been so much cooler if it was "spray."
‎如果是 “喷射”的话会更酷
Syd!
‎小希！
Oh!
Get out! Get out!
‎出去！
Go! Go! Go! Go!
‎走！
Oh my God! Please help me.
‎天啊 请帮帮我
Hey, Death. He's older than me.
‎带他走 他年纪比我大
The hydrogen peroxide combines with the acetic acid in bleach
‎过氧化氢和漂白剂中的乙酸
to make peracetic acid.
‎能形成过氧乙酸
Super corrosive.
‎腐蚀性极强
Oh no.
‎糟了
Wasn't there a giant spider on the roof when we walked in?
‎我们进来的时候 ‎屋顶上是不是有只巨大的蜘蛛？
Syd!
‎小希！
‎来吧！
Come on. Come on!
Oh sh--
Whoa!
Okay. Easy, spider. Okay, listen.
‎好 放轻松 蜘蛛 好吧 听着
I… I know you're pissed.
‎我知道你气坏了
I hated the ending of Charlotte's Web too.
‎我也讨厌《夏洛特的网》的结尾
They did Charlotte dirty. It should've been the pig.
‎他们骗了夏洛特 应该让猪死
‎希德妮！
Hey. Itsy-Bitsy.
‎嘿 小蜘蛛
-We've got to get out of here. -Okay.
‎-我们得离开这里 ‎-好
Okay.
‎好
‎桥谷镇肯定发生了不寻常的事
There's definitely something unusual going on in Bridge Hollow.
Oh, you think?
‎你看出来了？
But there has to be a logical, scientific explanation.
‎但一定有合理的科学解释
Did you not just see what happened in there?
‎你没看到里面发生了什么吗？
No, I… I saw it.
‎不 我看到了
‎显然 发生了一些疯狂的事
And clearly, there's something crazy going on.
But just because it's crazy doesn't mean it can't be explained.
‎但疯狂并不意味着无法解释
What are you talking about?
‎你在说什么？
‎爸爸 是什么事？
Dad, what is it?
It was Halloween 1985.
‎那是1985年万圣节
My friends and I, we were out trick-or-treating
‎我朋友和我在外面讨糖果
when they dared me to go into this abandoned building
‎他们激我进了一幢废弃的楼
to prove I wasn't chicken.
‎证明我不是胆小鬼
But I made a wrong step. I fell through the floorboards
‎但我走错了一步
‎我从地板掉进了地下室
into the basement.
‎然后我就看到了它们
And that's when I saw them.
‎骷髅 几百具
Skeletons.
Hundreds.
‎到处都是
They were everywhere.
‎他们还活着
And they were alive.
If that happened to you then,
‎如果当时你遭遇了这种事
‎为什么现在就不能发生？
why don't you think it's happening now?
Because it didn't happen to me.
‎因为那不是真的
‎一个月后 我上了科学课
A month later, I'm in science class.
My teacher tells us that a concussion can cause temporary hallucinations.
‎我的老师告诉我们 ‎脑震荡会导致暂时的幻觉
‎这就是答案
And that was the answer.
From that day on, I knew everything had an explanation.
‎从那天起 我就知道一切都有解释
‎-是科学 不是魔法 ‎-所以…
-It was science. Not magic. -So…
‎是“原来如此” 不是“天灵灵地灵灵”
It's "eureka!" Not "abracadabra."
‎那你跟我解释一下 ‎为什么长腿怪活了过来
Then explain to me how Granddaddy Long Legs came alive
and tried to eat us.
‎还想吃了我们
‎那个
Well,
maybe it was a gas leak causing mass hallucinations.
‎也许是煤气泄漏导致的幻觉
Or maybe it's Stingy Jack.
‎或者是吝啬鬼杰克
‎不管是什么 它都像病毒一样在蔓延
Well, whatever it is… it's spreading like a virus.
Which makes sense.
‎这就说得通了
‎因为它确实是从蝙蝠开始的
Because it did start with a bat.
Okay, hear me out. Let's just say hypothetically, this is Jack.
‎听我说 让我们假设这是杰克
Victoria said her grandmother trapped Jack inside that old lantern.
‎维多利亚说她奶奶 ‎把杰克困在那只旧灯笼里
‎也许我们可以做同样的事
Maybe we could do the same thing.
-Re-trap him. -Okay, let's say you're right.
‎-重新困住他 ‎-好吧 假设你是对的
Hypothetically, how do we go about doing something completely fictional
‎假设来说 ‎我们要怎么做完全虚构的事
and not at all real, like trapping a ghost?
‎比如困住鬼魂？
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎但有些孩子可能知道
But… I know some kids who might.
‎好了 小希 跟紧我
All right, Syd. Stay close.
Syd. Syd. Sydney.
‎小希 希德妮
‎太远了！
That's not close!
Hey, guys. Thanks again for helping me tonight.
‎嘿 大伙儿 再次感谢你们今晚来帮我
-Where are we? -Here's what we know.
‎-说到哪儿了？ ‎-我们掌握以下信息
‎如果你想困住鬼魂 就需要咒语
If you wanna trap a ghost, you're gonna need a spell.
‎最好是旧世界的罗姆咒语
Preferably an old-world Romani binding spell.
-Know any Gypsy witches? -Not any that are still alive.
‎-认识吉普赛女巫吗？ ‎-不认识活着的
Uh… Is that your dad?
‎那是你爸爸吗？
Sydney!
‎希德妮！
Ah.
Yeah.
‎对
Dad, guys. Guys, Dad.
‎老爸 朋友们 认识一下
Hi. What's up, players?
‎嗨 你们好吗？
Dap it up. Sideways. No?
‎碰个拳 不要？
‎不想？好吧
No love? Okay.
I like the costumes. Nice. Let me guess.
‎我喜欢你们的装扮 让我猜猜看
Uh… …Power Rangers.
‎超能战士
Madonna.
‎麦当娜
Uh… Puerto Rican Prince.
‎波多黎各猫王
You are so old.
‎你年纪大了
‎还有别的吗？
So anything else?
Yeah. I, uh, found this article online
‎对 我在网上找到一篇文章
that says when Madam Hawthorne died, they auctioned off some of her stuff.
‎说霍桑夫人去世时 ‎他们拍卖了她的东西
One of the items listed is her old grimoire. Spell book.
‎其中一个是她的魔咒书
I know.
‎我知道
‎就是它！爸爸 我们需要那本书
That's it! Dad, we need that book.
Okay, Rico Suave,
‎好 里科萨瓦
does the article say who bought it?
‎文章里有说是谁买的吗？
Yeah. This… fancy-pants antiques dealer.
‎说了 一个很厉害的古董商
‎谢尔顿斯金纳
Sheldon Skinner.
Oh, wait, guys. Skinner's here.
‎等等 斯金纳在这儿
Uh, he's wearing a Harvard sweatshirt and some of those go-to-hell pants.
‎他穿着哈佛套头衫和花裤子
He bought tickets for the Kreepy Karnevil in the pumpkin patch.
‎他刚在南瓜地买了恐怖嘉年华的票
Then we have to split up.
‎那我们必须分开
Okay. Take these.
‎好 拿着
What are go-to-hell pants? And am I wearing them?
‎花裤子长什么样？我穿的是吗？
‎（恐怖嘉年华）
Did you really mean what you said earlier about quitting the science team?
‎你之前说的退出科学小组是真的吗？
Dad, I don't know. It was really fun when I was younger,
‎爸爸 我不知道 ‎我小时候觉得挺有意思
and it was obvious you really wanted me to do it.
‎而且显然你想让我参加
Just like you really wanted me to do karate.
‎就像你想让我我学空手道一样
Step right up, ladies and ghouls, to a freak-tacular sideshow
‎女士们 食尸鬼们 ‎准备好迎接一场可怕至极
of thrills and chills, here in the Kreepy Karnevil.
‎充满惊声尖叫的“恐怖嘉年华”
That's not how you spell either of those words.
‎这两个词拼错了
‎（怪胎秀）
‎爸
Dad.
Look.
‎你看
That means Jack is here.
‎这说明杰克来了
‎你什么毛病？为什么要这么做？
-What's wrong with you?
Why would you do that?
‎我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
We thought you were someone else.
‎我们认错人了
Oh my God…
‎我的天啊
Oh, baby. I know. Okay.
‎宝贝 我知道 好
‎对 你们从来都不喜欢小丑
Yeah, you never really liked clowns.
Especially ones with axes.
‎特别是带着斧头的
Yeah.
‎等等 小希！
Wait, Syd!
They're just actors.
‎他们只是演员
Hey.
‎嘿
I don't think you're allowed to touch me unless I sign a waiver.
‎除非我签了协议书 不然你不能碰我
‎嘿 好吧
Hey. Okay.
Let's calm down now.
‎大家冷静一下
Just knocked your little infant friend out.
‎刚刚把你的小婴儿打晕了
These aren't actors?
‎那些不是演员吗？
Sydney, they aren't actors!
‎希德妮 他们不是演员！
‎重复！小丑不是演员！
-Repeat! The clowns are not actors!
So you no longer have the book.
‎所以书不在你这儿了
No, I sold it a while ago.
‎对 我之前卖了
I'd assumed Hawthorne's effects were of some value,
‎我本以为霍桑的遗产是有些价值的
but apparently, the only people who care about that junk
‎但显然 只有疯子和神神叨叨的人
are nutjobs and occultists.
‎在乎那种垃圾
No offense.
‎无意冒犯
When you say occultists, you mean like Satanists?
‎你说神神叨叨的人 ‎是指撒旦崇拜者？
Not like.
‎准确地说就是
Precisely.
Do you remember the name of the person you sold it to?
‎你记得买家的名字吗？
No, I don't remember his name,
‎我不记得他的名字 但他有送货地址
but he had a shipping address I will never forget.
‎我绝不会忘记
666 Elm Street.
‎埃尔姆街666号
Like I said, nutjobs.
‎就像我说的 疯子
Let's go to the ticket booth first.
‎我们先去展位 如果她不在那里…
-If she's not there-- -Killer clowns! Killer clowns!
‎杀手小丑！
-Uh, Sydney, what's going on? -Stingy Jack! He's here!
‎-希德妮 怎么回事？ ‎-吝啬鬼杰克！他来了！
-What? -Where?
‎-什么？ ‎-哪里？
Everywhere!
‎到处是！
Syd! No!
‎小希！不！
It's called the Halls of Horror.
‎这地方叫恐怖殿堂
Why couldn't you just go to the pumpkin patch?
‎你为什么不去南瓜地？
It's a dead end.
‎是死胡同
-Guys! Over here!
‎各位！这边！
Okay. Which way?
‎好 哪边？
Eeny, meeny, miney…
‎点点点麻子…
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
‎走！
Sydney!
‎希德妮！
Dad?
‎爸爸？
Sydney!
‎希德妮！
‎爸爸！
Dad!
Sydney!
‎希德妮！
Dad?
‎爸爸？
-Hey! Hey. It's me. It's me.
‎是我
‎爸爸！
Dad!
-It's okay, kiddo. -Look, there's an exit sign.
‎-没事的 孩子 ‎-那里有出口标志 我们快出去了
We're almost out.
All right. Back up. Back up.
‎对 退后
Okay, Bozo. I'm gonna wipe that crooked smile right off your face.
‎好了 小丑 我要抹掉你扭曲的笑容
Come on. Come on. Let you know, Homey don't play that.
‎来吧
‎告诉你 老子不吃这套
Oh!
‎爸爸！
Dad!
-Get him.
Ow!
Oh, night night!
‎晚安！很好
Oh, oh! Nice!
You know, I softened him up for you, but, uh, way to finish the job.
‎我帮你软化了他 但你结果得真漂亮
Sure, you did.
‎你才没有
Um, guys?
‎各位？
-Hey.
‎嘿
‎为什么一个小丑要带斧头？
Why does a clown need an axe anyway?
Go!
‎走！
To the right! That way! We parked out front.
‎往右边！那边！我们车停在前面
-Okay, now what? -Um, plan B. Bikes!
‎-好 现在怎么办？ ‎-B计划…自行车！
‎如果我爸知道怎么骑车就好了
Well, that would be great if my dad knew how to ride a bike.
‎真的吗？你不会骑车？
You don't know how to ride a bike?
I was taught books could take me wherever I needed to go.
‎我受到的教育是 ‎书可以带我去任何地方
Okay, bikes it is. Go! Go! Go!
‎好 就骑车了 走！
This thing is growing exponentially.
‎这玩意儿扩散速度太快
Each creature spreads it to another, which spreads it to another and another.
‎一个传一个
At its current rate, it'll take over Bridge Hollow by midnight.
‎照这速度 它会在午夜前占领桥谷镇
And according to Victoria, if we can't stop Jack by then,
‎根据维多利亚的说法 ‎如果我们不能阻止杰克
‎他会找到一个和他对掉的灵魂
he could find a soul to swap for his own.
Then every day will be Halloween.
‎那么每天都会是万圣节
-Maybe we should call the police. -Dad.
‎-要不咱们报警吧 ‎-爸
Do you really think the cops are going to believe any of this?
‎你觉得警察会信这些？
-You didn't even believe it. -Because it doesn't make sense.
‎-你都不信 ‎-因为这说不通
Not everything has to, Dad.
‎并非所有事都需要说得通 爸爸
‎大家引颈期盼的一刻来临了
And now the moment you've all been waiting for.
Who will be the face of this year's Stingy Jack?
‎谁会是今年吝啬鬼杰克的脸？
And the winner is…
‎优胜者是…
‎丹布朗！
Dan Brown!
Oh my God! Oh my God!
‎天啊！
In your face, Gary! In your face!
‎要你好看 盖瑞！
I did it, Ma! I did it!
‎我做到了 妈！我做到了！
We gotta! We gotta!
‎我们赢了！
-Tammy… -No, no, no, no.
‎-过来 ‎-不
Now let's get this guy up on old Stingy Jack.
‎让我们把这玩意儿 ‎装到吝啬鬼杰克头上
‎耶！
‎（埃尔姆街 死胡同）
-Okay, this is it. -No! No, no, no, no, no, no!
‎-就是这里 ‎-不！
Okay.
‎好
I'm gonna assume… that wasn't intentional.
‎我猜这不是故意的
‎骨头
Bones.
Why does it have to be bones?
‎为什么一定是骨头？
Um… You know, maybe… maybe I'll just stay right here.
‎我就留在这里吧
‎什么？不行 拜托
What? No, come on.
Whoa!
Okay.
‎好
Are we sure about this?
‎我们确定吗？
‎我从没见过真正的魔鬼崇拜者
I've never met a real devil worshiper before.
Should we be wearing crucifixes or something?
‎我们要不要戴个十字架？
Only one way to find out.
‎只有一条路
‎弗洛伊德校长？
Principal Floyd?
‎大家好啊 还有霍华德！
Well, hey there, everyone. And, Howard, what a pleasant surprise.
‎真是愉快的惊喜 ‎你们今晚都讨糖果了吗？
You all trick-or-treating tonight?
‎你们走运了
Well, you're in luck because this year, I've got…
miniature toothpastes.
‎因为今年我有迷你牙膏
‎所以 弗洛伊德
-So, uh, Floyd. -Uh-huh.
What are you some type of Satanist or something?
‎你是撒旦教徒吗？
-Oh jeepers. No, Howard. -What the hell?
‎天 才不是 霍华德
‎搞什么？
I'm a principal in a very small town with a very big Christian population.
‎我在居民多为基督教徒的小镇做校长
No, no, no. I just, uh, collect things.
‎不 我只是喜欢收集
You know, some people collect stamps. Some people collect butterflies.
‎有些人会集邮 有些人会收集蝴蝶
I collect objects
‎我收集和人类灵魂 ‎永恒诅咒有关的物品
related to the eternal damnation of the human soul.
Aha!
‎我相信这是你在找的
I believe this… is what you're looking for.
Okay, here it is.
‎好了 来吧
"Captus Exspiravit."
‎“Captus Exspiravit”
‎“Cum his verbis O spiritus”
"Cum his verbis O spiritus."
Dad. You know Latin. What does it say?
‎爸爸 你懂拉丁语 这是什么意思？
‎哦 圣灵 我用这些话
With these words, O spirit,
I banish you to captivity
‎把你放逐到囚禁之地
binding you to blah, blah, blah, blah…
‎将你束缚…
Right on. So how does it work?
‎正解 所以怎么运作的？
Well, it's your typical, run-of-the-mill binding spell.
‎就是你平常的束缚咒
You find a nice receptacle, right? Then you get close enough to your target.
‎找一个容器 接近你的目标
Be careful.
‎小心点
Then you say these magic words, and boom.
‎然后你说这些魔咒 嘭
-You've trapped yourself a ghost. -How close do we need to get?
‎-你就困住了一个鬼魂 ‎-我们得多接近？
I don't know. I mean, look,
‎我不知道
there's no hard-and-fast rules with these things.
‎这些东西没有严格的规定
I do know this.
‎我知道这个
When you say this spell, you have to believe it.
‎你念咒语时 必须真的相信
-Mm-hmm. -I mean, truly believe it.
‎要真心相信
‎全心全意
In your bones.
‎请告诉我你点了披萨
Please tell me you ordered pizza.
‎小费不能给多了
Oh, you must not tip well.
-Let's go, move it.
‎快走
-You just had to put helmets on them? -I thought it would be cute.
‎-你就非得给他们戴上头盔？ ‎-我觉得很可爱
Sydney! Save the grimoire!
‎希德妮！救救魔咒书！
Get the book out of here.
‎把书拿走
Syd!
‎小希！
‎我拿到了！
I got it!
The spell!
‎咒语！
-We gotta get out of here. -We can get out the back.
‎我们得走了 从后门走
No! Dad, we have to get that spell. It's the only way we can fix this.
‎不！爸 我们得拿到那个咒语 ‎只有这一个办法
We can't fix anything if we're dead. Now, come on and bring your little ass.
‎我们死了就什么都解决不了了 ‎赶紧给我走
-Let's go! Let's go! Come on! -Hurry!
‎-走！ ‎-快点！
‎快点！
‎走！进地下室！
Go! Get in the basement!
Go! Go! Go!
‎走！
Get in the basement!
‎进地下室！
-Go! -Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
‎-走！ ‎-走！
Mario, help him!
‎马里奥 帮帮他！
Dad. Do something!
‎爸 做点什么！
Dad! What is wrong with you?
‎爸爸！你有什么毛病？
The skeletons.
‎骷髅
-They're coming through. -What do we do?
‎-他们要打进来了 ‎-怎么办？
So it's unexplainable.
‎那是无法解释的
So what? They're real.
‎那又怎样？它们是真的
You know what you can do to something that's real?
‎你知道你能如何对付真实的东西？
You can kick its ass.
‎你可以好好教训它
You can take the girl out of Brooklyn,
‎你可以带一个女孩离开布鲁克林
but you can't take Brooklyn out the girl.
‎但你没法带走她骨子里的布鲁克林
Hey, Syd! Pop quiz.
‎嘿 小希！突击测验
You know what the chainsaw was originally called?
‎知道电锯最初叫什么吗？
A bone cutter.
‎切骨刀
Yeah.
‎好
This will do just fine.
‎这样就好了
Whoa!
Hmm? What the hell?
‎搞什么？
Ahhh!
Whoo!
Whoo, whoo, whoo. Whoo!
Ah!
Ahhh!
-Ahhh!
‎我的个老天爷啊 霍华德
Holy Lucifer, Howard.
Sydney, I take back everything I said about your dad.
‎希德妮 ‎我收回我说的关于你爸爸的一切
‎那是我这辈子见过最酷的事
That was the coolest thing I've ever seen in my whole life.
Boy, I hope somebody remembers these words.
‎天啊 希望有人记得这些咒语
‎那是什么？
What was that?
The Halloween decorations. They're gone.
‎万圣节装饰 它们不见了
But where did they go?
‎它们去哪了？
The Stingy Jack Festival.
‎吝啬鬼杰克节
He's building an army.
‎他在建立一支军队
‎妈
Mom.
These right here, Father,
‎神父 这些是
are egg-free coconut-pineapple scones.
‎不含鸡蛋的椰子菠萝烤松饼
-Ah, that's a home run, huh? -Yes!
‎-好厉害 ‎-对！
So…
‎所以…
‎我真的不该说谎
I'm really not supposed to lie.
Yeah! Love it!
‎耶！太爱了！
Mm-mm.
Oh, there's our pumpkin. Come on!
‎这是我们的南瓜 来吧！
Well… guess it's time to call it a night.
‎好 今晚该收摊了
Let's hear it for Stingy Jack!
‎为吝啬鬼杰克欢呼！
Stingy Jack. Stingy Jack. Stingy Jack.
‎吝啬鬼杰克
Which way do we go?
‎我们往哪走？
‎往那边走几个街区
It's still a few more blocks that way.
Or we can take the shortcut. Through the cemetery.
‎或者我们可以走捷径 穿过墓地
Okay. Let's go.
‎好 走吧
Oh, please tell me they don't decorate the cemeteries here.
‎拜托告诉我墓地里没有装饰
‎（桥谷镇公墓）
‎小希 你在做什么？
Hey, Syd. What are you doing?
-Come on, we have to find your mom. -And then what, Dad?
‎-快来 我们得找到你妈妈 ‎-然后呢 爸爸？
Stingy Jack has completely taken over Bridge Hollow.
‎吝啬鬼杰克已经完全控制了桥谷镇
And without Madam Hawthorne's spell, we can't stop him.
‎没有霍桑夫人的咒语 ‎我们无法阻止他
‎我们需要那个咒语
We need that spell.
What are you thinking?
‎你怎么想？
‎（霍桑）
I don't know, guys.
‎我不知道
I led the weekend séance at the community center a few times,
‎我在社区中心主导过几次招魂大会
but that was years ago.
‎但那是几年前的事了
Please, you have to try.
‎求你了 你得试试
Okay. Um, everybody, take hands.
‎好吧 大家手拉手
Oh! I can't believe I'm doing this.
‎真不敢相信我要这么做
But I am so here for it.
‎但我会做的
You know, channeling the… energy.
‎引导能量
-Whatever. -Thank you.
‎之类的
‎谢谢
Close your eyes.
‎闭上眼睛
Uh, now again, I'm very much out of practice--
‎再说一次 我已经生疏了…
Everyone.
‎所有人
Whoa.
‎霍桑小姐？
Miss Hawthorne?
‎约瑟芬霍桑小姐
Miss Josephine Hawthorne.
Are you in here?
‎你在这里吗？
Can you hear me?
‎你能听到我说话吗？
Of course I hear you, child.
‎我当然听见了 孩子
I'm not deaf. I'm dead.
‎我没有聋 我只是死了
Hell's bells, what have I done?
‎乖乖 我做了什么？
This is so going on TikTok.
‎我要发小视频了
Um, I released Stingy Jack.
‎我释放了吝啬鬼杰克
You did what?
‎你做了什么？
‎作为桥谷镇市长 我很荣幸
It is my honor as mayor of Bridge Hollow
to light this year's Stingy Jack.
‎能点燃今年的吝啬鬼杰克
Yeah. Light it up!
‎对 点燃它！
What on earth?
‎怎么搞的？
-Not good. -What's going on?
‎-怎么回事？ ‎-好了 各位
All right, everyone. Must have just blown a fuse or something.
‎可能是线路烧坏了
-Is somebody trippin'? -That is weird.
‎奇怪
What the H-E-C-K is that?
‎那是个啥呀？
Is this part of the show?
‎这也是表演的一部分吗？
Beats me, Father.
‎我也不懂啊 神父
I can't believe you nitwits
‎真不敢相信你们这些蠢货 ‎把那个恶魔放了出来
brought that dusty old demon back to life.
What are you going to do next? Bring back the black plague?
‎你们接下来要做什么？ ‎让黑死病卷土重来？
I don't know.
‎你们知道他会再试一次的吧？
You realize he's going to try to do it again?
To find a soul to take back
‎找到一个灵魂带回去
and trade with the devil so he can take over the world?
‎与魔鬼交换 好让他重新控制世界？
But this time, he won't let anyone stop him.
‎但这次 他不会让任何人阻止他
We can stop him.
‎我们可以阻止他
Oh!
And how do you propose to do this?
‎你打算怎么做？
You gonna hit him with your little broomstick?
‎你要用扫帚打他吗？
-Cast a little spell? -Exactly.
‎-施法？ ‎-没错
‎你书里的束缚咒
The binding spell from your book.
If you tell us the words, we can use it to re-trap Jack
‎如果你告诉我们咒语 ‎我们可以用它重新困住杰克
and put him away… forever.
‎永远赶走他
As you wish.
‎如你所愿
‎Cum his verbis O spirit us
Cum his verbis O spiritus
te ad captivitatem eccio.
‎te ad captivitatem eccio
Captivitatem.
‎Adligans te ad flammam diabalit
Adligans te ad flammam diabalit.
Got it.
‎录下了
Mm-hmm.
Good for you. Now can I please go back to being dead?
‎好样的
‎现在我能回去死了吗？
Oh, uh, yes, I'm sorry.
‎好的 对不起
Uh…
Oh, for the love of-- Where did you learn this?
‎看在上帝…你从哪学来的？
‎饼干盒子？
From a Cracker Jack box?
Amateurs.
‎真是外行
-What just happened? -Huh?
‎刚才怎么了？
‎我怎么闻起来像个老太太？
Why do I smell like an old white lady?
I know what's going on here.
‎我知道这是怎么回事了
It's those degenerates from Oaktown trying to sabotage our festival again.
‎奥克镇的小混混们 ‎又想破坏我们的节日了
Well, not this year.
‎今年就别想了
Nuh-uh.
-You can't hide behind that mask.
‎你们不能躲在面具后面
I could smell an Oaktownie from a mile away.
‎我老远就能闻到奥克镇人的味道
‎你知道为什么吗？
You know why?
Because you reek of sour grapes.
‎因为你们身上有酸葡萄味
-It's a bunch of Oaktownies. -We don't want you here.
‎我们不欢迎你们
‎我们不欢迎你们这些怪胎
We don't want any of you weird freaks.
You shouldn't have done that, clown boy.
‎你不该这么做 小丑
-They're everywhere. -I'm starting to hate Halloween.
‎-到处都是 ‎-我开始讨厌万圣节了
We got this.
‎我们可以的
Oh, Syd. Look. Over there.
‎小希 你看 那边
Mom's booth. Come on.
‎妈妈的摊位 来吧
‎安静
Quiet. Quiet.
Oh, dear Lord.
‎主啊
Where is she? Where's Mom?
‎她在哪里？妈妈呢？
I don't know!
‎我不知道！
And where's all the muffins and cookies and stuff?
‎松饼和饼干呢？
Maybe she sold them all and then went home.
‎也许她都卖光了 然后回家了
Okay, Syd. Pop quiz.
‎好 小希 突击测验
Where is the big pumpkin-headed statue thing
‎刚才那个大南瓜头
that was there just a minute ago?
‎雕像去哪儿了？
‎他走了
He's gone.
What time is it?
‎几点了？
It's almost midnight.
‎已经快半夜了
Dad, we need to find Jack before he takes someone's soul
‎爸 我们得在杰克掳走别人的灵魂前
back to the spirit world, or else we're screwed.
‎找到他 不然就完了
No, he can't.
‎他做不到
If he wants to trade a soul with the devil,
‎如果他想跟恶魔交换灵魂
he needs the lantern.
‎他就需要灯笼
And the lantern is back at the…
‎而灯笼在…
‎有人吗？
Hello?
I'm trippin'. I'm trippin'.
‎我疯了
So no one wants my baked goods.
‎没人想要我的点心
‎那我自己多吃点
Well, more for me.
Mmm.
Dad.
‎爸
-What? -What are you doing?
‎-干嘛？ ‎-你在做什么？
I'm looking for wheels.
‎我在找轮胎
A car, a truck, something.
‎车 卡车之类的都行
Anything.
I don't know.
Check for keys. Check.
‎检查钥匙
-Okay. Come on… -Nothing.
‎-好 拜托… ‎-没有
Hey. Never do this.
‎喂 你别学坏
Bypassing the ignition allows the positively charged battery
‎绕过点火系统 带正电的电池
‎能把带负电的电子推到启动机
to push the negatively charged electrons to the starter and…
‎然后…厉害吧
-Eureka.
Mm-hmm.
Don't tell Mom about this.
‎别跟妈妈说这个
All right.
‎好了
Let's go.
‎走吧
‎他们在干什么？
What are they doing?
Why are they just standing there?
‎他们为什么干站着？
The last time Jack tried to steal a soul, Madam Hawthorne stopped him.
‎杰克上一次试图偷灵魂时 ‎霍桑夫人阻止了他
So this time, he's using his army to make sure no one gets in his way.
‎所以这一次他要利用军队 ‎保证没人坏他好事
‎他会把我们留在这里直到半夜 ‎然后发起攻击
He'll keep us here till midnight then attack.
‎对 幸运的是 我们开着这辆夏南瓜
Yeah. Well, lucky for us, we're driving this Cucurbita pepo.
-Or, in layman's terms… -A squash.
‎-或者像外行人说的… ‎-窝瓜
Hang on.
‎等一下
Oh, here comes Charlotte!
‎夏洛特来了！
Oh!
‎美国最安全的小镇名号保不住了
Well, there goes this year's safest small town in the US.
Yes!
‎太好了！
Whoo!
That is really hard.
‎真的好硬
-Ugh.
Brains. Brains.
‎脑子…
-Brains. Brains.
Cum his verbis O spiritus…
‎Cum his verbis O spiritus…
Cum his verbis O spiritus.
‎Cum his verbis O spiritus
I tried to get you to learn Latin. Remember?
‎我想让你学拉丁文的 记得吗？
Dad, Latin is literally a dead language, and at that time, it seemed useless.
‎爸爸 拉丁语已经死了 ‎当时看起来很没用
Well, it's not so useless now, is it?
‎现在就有用了吧？
‎-你准备好了吗？好 ‎-好了
-You ready? Okay. -Ready.
-Hi, neighbor! -Oh!
‎嘿 邻居
Wondering what I'm doing in your bushes, right?
‎想知道我在你的草丛里做什么吗？
I'm not hiding if that's what you think.
‎我肯定不是躲在这儿做缩头乌龟
-Yeah, you are. -I'm not scared of anything.
‎-你是的 ‎-我什么都不怕
-You know what I mean? All right. -That's nice.
‎-很好 ‎-好吧
Hey, turns out you were right. I didn't turn into a zombie, huh?
‎看来你说得对 我没有变成僵尸
‎-你很幸运 ‎-万圣节 宝贝
-Lucky you. -Halloween, baby.
-Oh! -Oh! Oh…
It's your husband!
‎是你丈夫！
-Honey? -What was in that muffin? Cement?
‎-亲爱的？ ‎-那个松饼里是什么？水泥？
I get it. I get it. Baking isn't--
‎我懂了 烘焙不是…
-Look out!
‎小心！
Mom!
‎妈妈！
He breathes fire now?
‎他现在会喷火了？
Come on.
‎来吧
-Oh! Syd! Back up! Back up! Back up!
‎希德妮 退后！
Okay. All right.
‎好吧
You distract the bat. I'll save Mom.
‎你让蝙蝠分心 我去救妈妈
But, Dad, I have to do the spell.
‎可是爸爸 我得念咒语
Listen. It is too dangerous in there.
‎听着 里面太危险了
Now, I am still your father, and sometimes I still need to protect you.
‎我还是你的父亲 ‎有时候我还需要保护你
Okay?
‎好吗？
-Go! Save Mom! I got this. -Okay.
‎-走！去救妈妈！我可以的 ‎-好
‎好了 奥克人！来尝尝我们的厉害
All right, Oaktownies! Come get some!
I don't think you should be encouraging them, dear.
‎我觉得你不该鼓励他们
Don't get some! Don't get some! I changed my mind.
‎别来尝尝！我改变主意了
‎退后！
Stay back!
I'm thinking these things ain't from Oaktown.
‎我觉得这些东西不是奥克镇的
Dad! Hurry!
‎爸爸！快点！
‎我们没有时间了！
We're running out of time!
Ow.
‎好了 老鼠脸
All right, rat-face.
Round two. Ding ding.
‎第二回合 开始
Oh no! No!
‎糟了 不！
‎放开我！
Let me go!
I got you.
‎我抓到你了
Cum his verbis O spiritus
‎Cum his verbis O spiritus
te ad captivitatem eccio.
‎te ad captivitatem eccio
Adligans te ad flammam diabalit.
‎Adligans te ad flammam diabalit
Cum his verbis O spiritus
‎Cum his verbis O spiritus
te ad captivitatem eccio.
‎te ad captivitatem eccio
Adligans te ad flammam diabalit.
‎Adligans te ad flammam diabalit
-Howard! -I'm trying.
‎-霍华德！ ‎-我在努力
Dad, hurry!
‎爸爸！快点
At midnight his army is going to attack!
‎午夜时 他的军队会攻击！
I've said the spell! Twice! It's not working!
‎我念了咒语！两次！没用！
You have to truly believe!
‎你必须真的相信！
Dad! You can do it! I know you can!
‎爸爸！你可以的！我知道你可以！
Now cast that frigging spell!
‎现在念那该死的咒语！
‎哦 圣灵 我用这些话
With these words, O spirit,
I banish you to captivity…
‎把你放逐到囚禁之地
…binding you to the devil's flame!
‎将你束缚于恶魔的火焰！
‎天灵灵地灵灵
Abracadabra.
-They did it! -They trapped him!
‎-他们成功了！ ‎-他们把他困住了！
Oh, thank God. I thought they were screwed for sure.
‎谢天谢地 我以为他们肯定完蛋了
You see that?
‎你看见没？
‎我加入了新团队 宝贝！
I'm on a new team, baby!
-Welcome, son.
‎-欢迎 孩子 ‎-谢谢
Thank you.
Well-done, Oaktown. Well-done.
‎干得好 奥克镇
‎我们明年再见
We'll see you next year.
See you next year.
Oh!
-That's funny? -Yes.
‎-好笑吗？ ‎-是的…
‎别了 杰克
So long, Jack.
Wow, Mr. Gordon.
‎哇 戈登先生
‎我真希望我能看到 ‎你狠踹吝啬鬼杰克的屁股
I mean, I just wish I could've been there to see you whip Stingy Jack's ass.
Sorry, I meant "butt."
‎抱歉 我是说“臀部”
‎没关系 我确实狠狠修理了他
Nah, that's okay. I did whoop his ass.
‎我们修理了他 是团队合作
I meant, we whooped his ass. It was a team effort.
All right, who wants some cinnamon rolls?
‎好吧 谁想吃肉桂卷？
Whoo!
-Thank you! -Good luck.
‎谢谢！
‎祝你好运
Wow!
These are amazing.
‎太好吃了
-Incredible. -They are?
‎-难以置信 ‎-真的吗？
‎你应该开店的 戈登夫人
You should open a shop, Mrs. Gordon.
Wait a second.
‎等一下
Hmm.
Yo, what'd you put in this?
‎你放了什么？
Butter, sugar, gluten.
‎黄油 糖 面筋
‎在昨晚之后 我觉得人生太短了
I figured, after last night, life's too short.
I'm just happy that Halloween is over.
‎我很高兴万圣节结束了
You thought last night was crazy?
‎你以为昨晚就够疯狂了？
You should see what this town does for Christmas.
‎你该看看这个小镇的圣诞节
‎圣诞节？
Christmas?
Ho ho ho.
‎吼吼吼
I still say we should destroy that thing and be done with it.
‎我还是觉得我们应该毁掉那玩意儿
Dad, we went over this.
‎爸爸 我们讨论过了
If we destroy the lantern, we--
‎如果我们毁了灯笼 我们…
We could release Jack again. I know. I know.
‎可能会再次释放杰克 我知道
‎所以我才准备了磷酸铵
But see, that's why I got this.
Ammonium phosphate.
Flame retardant.
‎阻燃剂
Better be safe than sorry.
‎小心驶得万年船
Sounds like someone's a believer.
‎看来有人是信了
Hey.
‎嘿
Here.
‎给
You want me to lock it?
‎你要我锁上？
Yeah, and then I want you to take the key and keep it safe.
‎对 然后我要你把钥匙保管好
You're old enough now. You're old enough to do a lot of things.
‎你年纪够大了 可以做很多事
‎我会尽力记住这一点
And I'mma try my best to remember that.
‎谢谢 爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
You wanna join in or what?
‎你到底想不想加入？
-Oh, hell, no. -Oh, hell, no.
‎-不是吧 ‎-不是吧
‎字幕翻译：阿黛拉